MOCHAMMAD YUSUF FACHRONI

MOBILE DEVELOPER

yusuf.fachroni@gmail.com https://c0deslinger.github.io





Malang, Indonesia



https://linkedin.com/in/yusuf-fachroni

SUMMARY

Expert Mobile Developer bringing 10 years of expertise in Tech Industry, including 6 years of experience in Flutter and 4 years of experience in Java Spring Boot. Effectively manages assignments and team members. Dedicated to self-development to provide expectationexceeding service.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science - GPA 3.8 **Muhammadiyah Malang University** 2011-2016

SKILLS

- Flutter (Bloc, Cubit, Riverpod, Getx, Firebase, Graphql, Rest, Google Map)
- · Android Native (Java, Kotlin, MVVM)
- Java Backend (Spring boot)
- Web (ReactJS, Tailwind CSS)
- · Database (Mysql, Redis, Firestore, SOLite)
- Design Tool (Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop)

HONOR & AWARDS

Please click for the documentation

- 1st Place Cyber Defence Competition (2015) by Kementrian Pertahanan (Ministry of Defense) Republic Indonesia
- Finalist of Gemastik 8 Embedded System Competition (2015) by Direktorat Jendral Pendidikan Tinggi (The Directorate General of Higher Education) Republic Indonesia
- Finalist of National Cyber Jawara Competition (2015) by Kementerian Komunikasi dan Informatika (Ministry of Communication and Information Technology of the Republic of Indonesia.) Republic Indonesia
- Finalist of Gemastik 7 Software Development Competition (2014) by Direktorat Jendral Pendidikan Tinggi (The Directorate General of Higher Education) Republic Indonesia
- Finalist of National Cyber Jawara Competition (2014) by Kementerian Komunikasi dan Informatika (Ministry of Communication and Information Technology of the Republic of Indonesia.) Republic Indonesia
- Finalist of Gemastik 6 Game Competition (2013) by Direktorat Jendral Pendidikan Tinggi (The Directorate General of Higher Education) Republic Indonesia

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Technical Lead

ForU AI (Web3) - Singapore

June 2024 - Present

- Generated the idea and developed prototypes using Flutter for a Telegram Mini
- Led the tech team in development and deployment while also assisting in preparing comprehensive technical documentation to ensure clear system specifications for the development team.

Techlead & Senior Mobile Developer

Untukmu. AI Pte. LTD - Lavender Street, Singapore

February 2023 - Present

- Developed an Al-powered gift-giving mobile application (Al Marketplace) from scratch using Flutter (GetX, Flavor, Firebase, Socket.IO, Google Maps API, Google & Apple Sign-In).
- Led requirements analysis to ensure a deep understanding of business needs, enhancing user experience.
- Successfully delivered the application, achieving more than 50,000 active users with a perfect 5-star rating on Google Play Store and App Store.

Senior Mobile Developer

CFund Asia - Jakarta, Indonesia

January 2022 - February 2023

- Develop CFund App (Crypto Investment) with Flutter (Riverpod, Flutter Hook, Firebase, Graphql)
- Collaboration with backend developers on API Integration, implement advanced design from UI/UX designers, and manage teamwork to produce high quality solutions.

Java Developer

Exel Sistem Solusindo - Malang, Indonesia

September 2017 - December 2021

- Develop Telkomsel MyAds Services (API Server, Short URL, Display Ads, SMSC & MMSC Adapter, Broadcast LBA, ESB Connector) with Java Springboot
- Develop Telkomsel Mobile Banking Platform Services (Smart Reminder, Service Reminder, Loan Engine) with Java Springboot

Senior Android Developer

Unimasoft - Malang, Indonesia

January 2017 - December 2022

- Develop Aplikasi Satu Data Keluarga Android App for Dinkes (Public Health Office) Kab. Malang with Android Native (Java MVC. Firebase, Map API)
- Develop Surveilans Epidemiologi Terpadu Berbasis Masyarakat Android App for Dinkes (Public Health Office) Malang with Android Native (Kotlin MVVM, Map)

Senior Android Developer

Brixzen - Malang, Indonesia

April 2016 - September 2021

- Develop Android application "Go Sigap Panic Button" for Police Department with Android Native (Java)
- Develop Coal Mine Management System Android app for PT Lestari Cipta Persada with Flutter (Bloc)
- Develop Siaga Panic Button Hybrid App (Android & iOS) for Police department with Flutter (Cubit)

Mobile Game Developer

Edukasimu - Malang, Indonesia

February 2016 - January 2018

- · Design and Code mobile educational game with Unity3d
- Designed characters, levels and other elements to enhance players gaming experience.

Founder & Developer

Paperplay Studio - Malang, Indonesia

September 2014 - May 2021

- Developed 26 mobile apps and games, several of which surpassed 100K-500K downloads (Unity, Figma, Firebase, AdMob Integration).
- Managed all aspects of product design and development, including quality assurance, user experience, monetization, and deployment on Google Play Store and App Store.
- Recognized as a Top Developer in the Intel NDK Education Challenge.

MOCHAMMAD YUSUF FACHRONI

PORTFOLIO

yusuf.fachroni@gmail.com https://c0deslinger.github.io Malang, Indonesia







https://linkedin.com/in/yusuf-fachroni

Untukmu AI - Hybrid (iOS and Android) Mobile App

Al gift-giving application (Marketplace) with 10000 download Flutter, Getx State management, Firebase, Google Map API, Apple Sign In

CFund Asia - Hybrid (iOS and Android) Mobile App

Crypto Investment Application

Flutter, Riverpod, Flutter Hook, Firebase, Graphql

Brixzen - Coal Mine Management System

Android application for managing coal transaction for PT Lestari Cipta Persada

Android Flutter, Firebase Cloud Messaging, Flutter BLoC

Brixzen - Panic Button Polres Gresik

Panic button application for Polres Gresik with feature send help request, request SKCK, list of police office based on location, list of hospital, etc

Android java native, Firebase Cloud Messaging, Google Map

Brixzen - iKontraktor

Android applicator for management of construction projects, from planning and development to completion

Android Flutter, Firebase Cloud Messaging, Flutter GetX

Unima Soft - Aplikasi Satu Data Keluarga Dinkes Malang

Android application for survey civil health condition for Dinas Kesehatan Kab Malang (Public Health Office)

Android native with Java, MVC, SQLite, Http client

Unima Soft - Surveilans Epidemiologi App Dinkes Malang

Android application for survey epidemic condition for Dinas Kesehatan Kab Malang (Public Health Office)

Android native with Kotlin, MVVM, SQLite, Http client

Unima Soft - E Sakip

Android application for Dinas Perumahan, Kawasan Permukiman dan Cipta Karya kab Malang, to aid in managing and monitoring the agency's performance

Flutter, GetX, Firebase Cloud Messaging

Paperplay Studio - Kuis Cerdas Cermat

Trivia Edu Game that features hundreds of quiz questions based on categories such as mathematics, science, social studies, language, technology, etc

Unity 3D with C#, Adobe Illustrator

Paperplay Studio - Learn Quran

Android educational games for childern to learn quran from Hijaiyah letter to tajweed

Unity 3D with C#, Adobe Illustrator

Exel Sistem Solusindo - Telkomsel MBP Service Reminder

Scheduling reminder for mobile banking platform to Top up balance based on balance limit and time period Java Springboot, Unit Testing (JUnit & Mockito), MySQL,

Apache Http Client

Exel Sistem Solusindo - Telkomsel MBP ESB Connector

Connector adapter for handling request from MBP Core to ESB

Java Springboot, Unit Testing (JUnit & Mockito), MySQL, Apache Http Client

Exel Sistem Solusindo - Telkomsel MBP Loan Engine

Api Service to handling loan balance request on mobile banking transaction

Java Springboot, Unit Testing (JUnit & Mockito), MySQL, Apache Http Client

Exel Sistem Solusindo - Telkomsel Myads Api Server

Api Service for processing broadcast SMS/MMS/USSD using REST api request

Java, Spark Java Http Server, Unit Testing (JUnit & Mockito), MySQL, Redis Client, Kafka Client

Exel Sistem Solusindo - Telkomsel Myads Display Ads

Service for provide digital display advertising on Internet websites, apps or social media through banners or other advertising formats made of images and video

Java, Spark Java Http Server, Unit Testing (JUnit & Mockito), MySQL, Redis Client

Exel Sistem Solusindo - Telkomsel Myads Channeldelivery

Adapter for handling send SMS to SMSC, MMS to MMSC, and USSD to USSD Gateway

Java, Spark Java Http Server, Unit Testing (JUnit & Mockito), MySQL, Kafka Client, Apache Http Client

Exel Sistem Solusindo - Telkomsel Myads Broadcast LBA

Service for processing broadcast SMS/MMS/USSD based on user location

Java, Spark Java Http Server, Unit Testing (JUnit & Mockito), MySQL

Edukasimu - Learn Ouran

Android educational games for childern to learn quran from Hijaiyah letter to tajweed

Unity 3D with C#, Adobe Illustrator

Edukasimu - Learn to Dua'

Android educational games for childern to learn dua' for children

Unity 3D with C#, Adobe Illustrator